Guide to the New York Woman Suffrage collection, 1914-1915.
New York Woman Suffrage collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York Woman Suffrage collection, 1914-1915.
8041
.1 cubic ft.
Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes flyers and broadsides regarding Woman Suffrage movement.
Collection is likely the archive of Mrs. Henry White Cannon (Jennie O. Curtis), who chaired the Delaware County Committee of the New York Woman Suffrage Association, Sixth District. The Committee, based in Delhi, N.Y. (the county seat of Delaware County) formed in 1913. It includes materials distributed as part of its organizing efforts together with reports on its success. The Sixth District was headed by Harriet B. Owens, who received a Ph.D. in mathematics in 1910.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes (1) flyers and broadsides: "Attention!...Cakes for Sale" [ca. 1914]; "Votes for Women 46th Annual Convention of the New York State Woman Suffrage Association and General Conference of New York State Suffragists" [ca. 1914]; "Equal Suffrage One Section of the State Wide Pilgrimage" [ca. 1914]; "TONIGHT Votes for Women Hancock is highly honored to have Beatrice Forbes Robertson Hale..." [ca. 1914-1915]; "To-Morrow Night Tues, Oct. 5th at Opera House A Mass Meeting in the Cause of Equal Suffrage" [ca. 1915]: "Important Meeting Tonight!..." [ca. 1914-1915]; "Constitution Explained" [ca. 1914-1915]; and, "To the Delegates of the National Woman Suffrage Association;" (2) a suffrage enrollment mailing with a flyer ("Explanatory"), "All Year Round Resolutions for Suffragists" by Alice Duer Miller; and an enrollment card with a blank return envelope; (3) a fair copy of "The Widow's Thirds" by Aunt Patty, a verse monologue dramatizing unfair probate laws which deny equity to widows and the typescript of cheerful doggerel promoting "The Equal Suffrage Headquarters" available to all-comers in Delhi; (4) three suffrage plays: typescript of Mrs. Frederic C. Howe's THE PERFECT LADY; typescript of Florence Kiper's CINDERELLINE OR THE LITTLE RED SLIPPERS; and a copy of Jessie Trimble's THE END OF THE BATTLE; (5) typescripts of drafts for speeches and reports on grassroots initiatives in Delaware County, principally during 1914; and (6) two broadsides related to the work of the Consumers' League on child labor and minimum wage standards.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cannon, Henry White,; Hale, Beatrice Forbes Robertson.; Howe, Frederic C.,; Kiper, Florence.; Miller, Alice Duer.; Owens, Harriet B.; Trimble, Jessie.; Consumers' League.; New York State Woman Suffrage Association.; New York Woman Suffrage Association.Sixth District (Delaware County)
Subjects:
Women--Suffrage--United States--History--20th century.; Women--Suffrage--United States--Societies, etc.; Women--Suffrage--New York (State)--Delaware County.; Women--Suffrage--New York (State)--Delhi.; Child labor.; Minimum wage.
Places:
Delhi (N.Y.)--Politics and government.; Delaware County (N.Y.)--Politics and government
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Broadsides, flyers and leaflets
  - Flyer: "ATTENTION! … CAKES FOR SALE", 1914-; 8-1/2 x 9"; printed black on pale orange stock (Box 1)
  - Leaflet: "Votes for Women / Woman Suffrage Conference and School", 1914; Empire State Campaign Committee; 8 x 10"; printed black on off-white stock (Box 1)
    >Ithaca, NY
  - Leaflet: "Votes for Women / 46th Annual Convention of the New York State Woman Suffrage Association and General Conference of New York State Suffragists", 1914; New York State Woman Suffrage Association; 9-1/4 x 12-1/2"; printed black on off-white stock (Box 1)
    >New York
  - Flyer: "Equal Suffrage One Section of the State Wide Pilgrimage…", 1914; 10-3/8 x 6-3/16"; printed black on off-white stock (Box 1)
  - Small Broadside: "TONIGHT Votes for Women Hancock is highly honored to have Beatrice Forbes Robertston Hale…", 1914-1915; 10-1/4 x 4-11/16"; printed black on light green stock (Box 1)
  - Flyer: "To-Morrow Night Tues., Oct. 5th at Opera House A Mass Meeting in the Cause of Equal Suffrage…", 1915; 8-1/2 x 5-1/2"; printed black on tan stock (Box 1)
  - Flyer: "Important Meeting To-Night!...", 1914-1915; 9-3/8 x 5-1/2"; printed black on tan stock (Box 1)
  - Flyer: "Constitution Explained…", 1914-1915; 9-1/2 x 6-1/2"; printed black on tan stock (Box 1)
  - Handbill: "To the Delegates of the National Woman Suffrage Association.", Undated; 8 x 6"; printed black on off-white stock (Box 1)
  - Flyer: "Woman Suffrage and Temperance.", Undated; Southern Tier Suffrage Press; 9-1/8 x 4-7/8"; printed black on pink stock (Box 1)
    >Hornell, NY
  - Flyer: "Explanatory …", 1914-1917; 7 x 5-1/2"; printed blue on white stock (Box 1)
  - Card: Miller, Alice DuerCard: Miller, Alice Duer. "All Year Round Resolutions for Suffragists.", Undated; 3-1/2 x 5-1/2"; printed blue on white card stock (one side) (Box 1)
  - Enrollment card, "New York State Woman Suffrage Party, Undated; 3-1/4 x 5-1/2"; printed black on white card stock (Box 1)
- Suffrage/Women’s Rights Play and Verse
  - Howe, Mrs. Frederic C. Typescript: THE PERFECT LADY A One Act Play, Undated; 11 x 8-3/4"; 15 pp; brown wrappers (bradbound) (Box 1)
  - [(Frank), Kiper, Florence] Typescript: CINDERELLINE OR THE LITTLE RED SLIPPERS, Undated; 11-3/4 x 9-1/4"; 21 pp; brown wrappers, with the title penned in ink at the front cover (Box 1)
  - [Stone, Jane (pseud., Jessie Trimble]. THE END OF THE BATTLE A Play in One Act., 1913; The Cooperative Press; 6-3/4 x 5-1/4"; 20 pp; off-white stapled wrappers (Box 1)
  - Mss. (Fair copy): "The Widow’s Thirds" By Aunt Patty., Undated; 11 x 8-1/2"; 5 pp; off white stock (Box 1)
  - Carbon Typescript, "The Equal Suffrage Headquarters" (2 copies), 1913-1917; Delaware County Equal Suffrage Association; 11-3/8 x 7-7/8"; onion-skin typing paper (Box 1)
    >Delhi, New York
- Delaware County Reports, Speeches and Notes
  - Typescript: 1913 Report, 1913; New York State Woman Suffrage Party, Sixth District – Delaware County; 11 x 8-1/2"; 5 pp; off-white typing paper (Box 1)
  - Report: "The Suffrage Movement in Delaware County, 1914; 10-1/2 x 8"; 6 pp; off-white typing paper (Box 1)
  - Speech: "What is the object of this Convention?", 1914; 10-1/2 x 8"; 3 pp; off-white typing paper (Box 1)
  - Carbon typescript: "The Equal Suffrage Campaign in Delaware opens with a Convention…", 1914; 10-7/8 x 8-1/2"; 1 pp; off-white typing paper (Box 1)
  - Report: "The movement in Delaware County is only 2-1/2 years old…", 1914; 11 x 8-1/2"; 2 pp; off-white typing paper (Box 1)
  - Address: "The New York State Women Suffrage Association held its first Convention…", 1914; 10-1/2 x 8"; 3 pp; white onionskin typing paper (Box 1)
  - Address: "VICTORY IN 1915!", 1914; 11 x 8"; 1 pp; white onionskin typing paper (Box 1)
  - Mss. Holograph Notes on Woman Suffrage., 1913-1915; 10 x 8"; 5 pp; off-white writing paper (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - "Adding Up.", Undated; 4-3/4 x 7-11/16"; typed text pasted to stiff card stock (Box 1)
  - Notes., 1915-08-25; 6-7/8 x 6"; 2 pp; on stationery engraved “Delhi, New York" at the upper margin (Box 1)
- Non-Suffrage Materials
  - Consumers’ League. Broadside: "Working Women of the State Is the Public Not to Know the Facts.", 1914; Consumers’ League; 15 x 8-1/2"; printed black on off-white newsprint (Box 1)
    >New York City
  - Broadside: "Child Labor and Factory Commission Continuation Bills Held up by Assembly Rules Committee.", 1914-03-21; 10-1/2 x 8-1/2"; printed black on off-white news print (Box 1)